ADRIAN@AFTRE.NET GITHUB.COM/AAFTRE

Adrian Maliszewski



About me

Over fifteen years of experience in systems integration of network multifunction devices and networked print and imaging services. Passionate for IT problem solving with methodical in-depth analysis, creative brainstorming with an incessant drive to build systems, tools, and innovate. Dedicated to earning the trust of all stakeholders. I believe talent is often hard work in disguise.

Work Experience

November 2020 - Present

Full Stack Developer & Unix Administrator Xerox Canada @ Bell Canada (Remote) Montreal, QC

- Worked to review and remediate security audits of networks services, servers, and web applications.
- Migrated applications to AWS Elasticbeanstalk, Opensearch, RDS, EC2, VPC, VPN, OpenVPN.
- Implemented data synchronization, import and update processes using Python and Elasticsearch / Opensearch.
- Implemented business rule specifications using PHP, Javascript, HTML, CSS and Laravel Framework.
- Implemented exports of SQL table data into Microsoft Excel spreadsheet workbooks using PHP.
- Upgraded Laravel applications to current framework releases.
- Automated backup of SQL databases to remote NAS over SSH with data encryption at rest.
- Created and supported SQL stored procedures and schemas.
- Developed interactive PDFs using JavaScript.
- Supported VueJS Single Page Applications using JSON RESTful APIs.
- Supported OpenText Exstream print data processing OpenSuse server using Unix shell scripts and utilities.
- Created Docker containers.
- Interviewed prospective candidates.

January 2013 - Present

Operations Manager & System Analyst Xerox Canada @ Walmart Canada Mississauga, ON

Accomplishments

- Oversaw projects deploying 100s of network multifunction devices across over 400 nationwide locations.
- Developed a proactive consumable audit process generating reports from scraped website data which was later deployed as company-wide best practice. Implemented using PHP, BASH, and curl.
- Developed streamlined service call tracking and proactive consumable delivery processes using VBA.
- Collected packet captures using Wireshark and tcpdump. Analyzed postscript print data, submitted and managed engineering escalations to develop customized firmware compatible with the customer's environment.
- Used Powershell and SNMP to monitor device status and deploy configuration changes.
- Integrated device configuration with customer environment to support scan to network and secure print workflows.
- Facilitated device network security scanning, liaised with Xerox security to ensure adherence to network requirements.

Responsibilities

- Managed onsite helpdesk team supporting a fleet of over 3000 devices in diverse environments.
- Provide mentorship, leadership and motivation.
- Managed key contact and direct report escalations from inception to resolution.
- Administered Equitrac servers, Microsoft Windows print servers, queue and driver settings.
- Integrated helpdesk call flow between customer, service partner and Xerox.
- Co-ordination of contractual deliverables with service partners and technical services across Canada.
- Provide on-site services delivering a high level of customer service satisfaction, and the successful account operation.
- Internal process creation and management required to enable operational excellence and seamless service delivery.
- Supported long and short-term account and business development strategies identifying risk, opportunity and understanding of customer requirements.
- Built shared email, storage and phone service infrastructure to enable and promote team collaboration.
- Built and maintained client relationships across all stakeholders.
- Responsible for account P&L management, execution of strategy to achieve operating targets.

February 2004 - January 2013 Print Operations Support Site Lead Xerox Canada @ Mackenzie Financial

Toronto, ON

Accomplishments

- Developed a network file management Windows Service solution written in C.
- Developed a print-to-department accounting chargeback system written in Perl.
- Developed BASH shell scripted process using ImageMagick to convert PDF documents to JPEG thumbnails for web use.
- Involved with various development projects requiring data analysis and customer consultation.
- Conducted technical support tasks for software and network operation.

Responsibilities

- Site management duties, employee leadership and mentoring, key customer contact.
- Issue tracking, escalation and progress reporting using Remedy ticketing system.
- Operated Xerox 4890, 4635, DC260, Nuvera 100EA printing equipment, the Barr Enterprise Print Server and the IBM z/OS Mainframe SDSF system.
- Completed design and modification of forms, fonts using Elixir suite.
- Responsible for JSL programming of IBM Mainframe LCDS for use on Xerox Printers.
- Interdepartmental liaison, scheduling of tasks, completion of documentation.
- Trained staff on BARR Server operation, mainframe operation, and all operating procedures.
- Developed, implemented and documented disaster recovery and business continuity procedures, all operating procedures.

Technical experience and skills

Operating Systems

- Wintel family: Windows 10, Server 2008 R2.
- Unix: FreeBSD, OpenBSD, Linux (Debian, Kali, Redhat).

Server Products

- Web server: NGINX, Apache, Laravel, VueJS, Wordpress CMS.
- Database: MySQL, MariaDB, PostgreSQL, LDAP.
- Network: Equitrac, Proxmox, PRTG, Docker, QEMU, OpenVPN, Let's Encrypt, Bind, ISC-DHCP, Icecast.

Software Engineering

• Programming Languages: PHP, Python, CSS, VBA, Powershell, JavaScript, C, C++, Perl, Bash, HTML, XML, YAML, JSON.

Network Engineering

- Communication Protocols: TCP/IP, SNMP(v3), RIP, OSPF, FTP, HTTP(S), POP, SSH, DHCP, NetBIOS, NFS, SMB, Kerberos
- Firewall: PF, IPF, IPTables.

Miscellaneous

• Software: Service Now & Remedy Ticketing Systems, Wireshark, tcpdump, nmap, Oracle Virtualbox, VMWare Workstation, Hyper-V, Virtual PC, Elixir Suite, Microsoft Office Suite; Excel, Word, Powerpoint, Visio.

Education

November 2019 CCNA Routing and Switching Certification – 200-125 Cisco ID: CSC013138782

- Achieved CCNA certification through self-study.
- Cisco Certified Network Associate (CCNA) validates the ability to install, configure, operate, and troubleshoot mediumsize route and switched networks, including implementation and verification of connections to remote sites in a WAN. Able to install, configure, and operate LAN, WAN, and dial access services for small networks.
- Working knowledge of IP, IPv6, RIP, OSPF, EIGRP, BGP, VLANs, Ethernet, Access Lists.

March 2003 Computer Network Engineering Xerox Canada

- Completed Computer Networks Engineering Technician program with a 4.35 / 5.00 GPA.
- Completed a 2-year college diploma in 12 months, through an accelerated learning program.
- Over 550 hours of practical and individualized lab completed.
- Program is OACETT & CTAB accredited.

July 2000 CCNA Certification

• Achieved CCNA certification through self-study.

REFERENCES AVAILABLE UPON REQUEST